## Kariyma Murphy

## Frontend Developer

kariymamurphy.com / kariymam@proton.me

## **Professional Summary**

Frontend Developer / Creative Technologist with 7+ years of experience leading UI / UX design projects and connecting engineering, product, and design teams to drive measurable results. Career supported by digital products with a strong focus on user-centered design methods and NPower technical training in full-stack development.

Tech	nical	Pro	iects
1 ((1)	milli	110	

Technical Projects				
	Weather App React, Node.js	MernFood   NPower Capstone MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js		
Work Experience				
May 2022 - Present	Freelance, Self Employed — Remote			
	• Partners with research teams and small business clients over 7 years to deliver designs that unlock brand potential. (AdobeCreative Suite: Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Lightroom)			
	<ul> <li>Created digital marketing materials to increase participant engagement in a PCORI-funded study, including an interactive augmented reality filter to teach younger audiences about heart health, reaching 500k interactions. (Meta Spark AR)</li> </ul>			
Feb 2021 - Aug 2022	Principal Designer, Capital One — McLean, VA (Remote)			
	• Led user interface design for an enterprise app that, in pilot, drove up business efficiency by cutting requests processing time in half and saved employees approximately 500 hours monthly.			
	• Conducted quantitative and qualitative testing with +60 participants, exceeding NPI targets, while influencing frontend roadmap for anticipating ADA and privacy compliance. (Figma, usertesting.com)			
	<ul> <li>Coordinated cross-functional reviews across 3 divisions and advocated for ongoing UX research which increased buy-in for UX-centric solutions.</li> </ul>			
May 2020 - Dec 2020	Senior UI Designer, Truist — Atlanta, GA (Remote)			
	<ul> <li>Designed +200 UI mockups and optimized hand-off resulting in more efficient feature delivery on a high-speed schedule following a merger and company rebrand. (Adobe XD)</li> </ul>			
	Delivered consistent features as	nd copywriting on 3 device sizes and 2 operating systems (iOS, Android).		
Oct. 2017 - Apr. 2020	Transformation Delivery Consul	tant, KPMG — Baltimore, MD (Hybrid)		
		aS implementations to user-centric solutions, and supported sales demos curing +\$1M in future contracts. (Sketch, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe		
Key Skills				

UX & UI Prototyping • Interaction design • Product development • Usability testing • Graphic design • Web and mobile design systems • Writing user requirements • Agile • Project management. Technical languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Typescript, Python Tools/Frameworks: Figma, Penpot, Blender, HTMX, PostCSS, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, Eleventy, Astro, Jira, Rally, Sharepoint, Teams, Slack, Excel/Numbers/Sheets/Powerpoint, UserTesting, Git, and Github.com. Operating systems: macOS, iOS, Android.

## Education

Path2Tech Full Stack Development Program, NPower Design Research & Writing Intensive, School of Visual Arts Design Bachelor's, Graphic Design, Maryland Institute College of Art